
================ casey_schulz_raw.json ================
{{Infobox character
|games       =FOTV
|image       =FOTV Vault 31 Cryobay.png
|race        =[[Human]]
|gender      =Male/Female
|family      =
|location    =[[Vault 31]]
|role        =Junior executive
|affiliation =[[Vault 31]]/[[Vault-Tec Corporation]]
|TV actor    =
|dod         =
|dod verified=
}}

'''Casey Schulz''' is a pre-War junior executive of the [[Vault-Tec Corporation]] who was part of the "[[Bud's Buds]]" program in [[Vault 31]].

==Background==
Schulz was a Vault-Tec junior employee selected to participate in [[Bud Askins]]' executive assistant training program "[[Bud's Buds]]," a plan to create "super managers" who would define the future of humanity after the [[Great War]] wiped out all competitors to Vault-Tec. Schulz and the other Buds would be kept in [[Cryonics|cryostasis]] in Vault 31, periodically thawed out, and transferred to [[Vault 32]] or [[Vault 33|33]] to manage the dwellers and participate in controlled breeding (eugenics), all under Askins' supervision.<ref>[[Norm MacLean]]: ''"So what's Vault 32 and 33? Just people to be controlled?"''<br />[[Bud Askins]]: ''"What? No! When you put it like that, it sounds downright morally questionable. They're our breeding pool, the ultimate expression of HR R&D. Genetically selected to breed with my Buds to create a class of super managers. People with positivity, people who make lemonade. People who will inherit the Earth after we've wiped the surface clean."''<br />("[[The Beginning]]")</ref><ref name="highly supervised">[[Norm MacLean]]: ''"Is this where my dad's from?"''<br />[[Bud Askins]]: ''"You'll never find out. Oh. He's gonna find out. These are Bud's Buds. My Buds. America outsourced the survival of this country to the private sector. But it would have been insane to keep a failed nation alive. So, we kept Vault-Tec alive instead. A well-trained staff of highly supervised junior executives from my own assistant training program. Because the future of humanity comes down to one word: Management."''<br />("[[The Beginning]]")</ref> As of [[Timeline (2250-2300)#2296|2296]], more than 219 years after the [[Great War]], they remained dormant in stable condition in [[Vault 31]]'s cryo pods<ref name="fotv107">[[Fallout (TV series)|''Fallout'']], "[[The Radio]]"</ref> until [[Norm MacLean]] initiated the process to thaw eighteen of the junior executives from their pods in response to Bud Askins' threats<ref name="fotv201">[[Fallout (TV series)|''Fallout'']], "[[The Innovator]]"</ref> which included Schulz's pod.<ref name="fotv202">[[Fallout (TV series)|''Fallout'']], "[[The Golden Rule]]"</ref> 

==Appearances==
Casey Schulz appears only {{in|FOTV}}.

==References==
{{References}}

[[Category:Fallout TV series mentioned-only characters]]
[[Category:Fallout TV series human characters]]
[[Category:Vault 31 characters]]
[[Category:Vault-Tec characters]]

================ cassandra_hawthorne_raw.json ================
{{Infobox character
|games       =FOTV
|image       =Cassandra Hawthorne.png 
|race        =[[Human]]
|gender      =Female
|family      =[[Lloyd Hawthorne]] - husband {{Icon|dead}}
|dob         =
|location    =
|affiliation =[[Vault 4]]
|TV actor    =[[Angel Desai]]
|stunt double=[[Tricia Guarin]]
|status      =Deceased
|occupation  =Genetic researcher
}}

'''Cassandra Hawthorne''' is a character {{In|FOTV}}.

==Background==
Cassandra was one of the many scientists assigned to work in Vault 4 to research the effects of [[radiation]] on [[human]] DNA.

==''Fallout'' TV series==
===[[The Trap]]===
Cassandra, her husband [[Lloyd Hawthorne]], and two unnamed children appear in a commercial advertisement for [[Vault 4]]. They appear eating dinner at their table, where [[The Ghoul|Cooper Howard]] joins them. He tells the viewers that she and her husband are both scientists who will be studying the effects of Radiation on Human DNA. Cassandra confirms it and notes that they'll be living in Vault 4, leading a community led by scientists.

The commercial continues, and a talk between Lloyd and Cooper occurs about how they, along with eighty other volunteer scientists, will be working there for the next five years. This is to ensure that regardless of what happens, [[United States of America|America]] will be ready for whatever happens. Hearing this, Cooper compliments the family for being the true heroes rather than him, who plays them in the movies.

Once the commercial ends, Cassandra notes how she and Lloyd were so nervous throughout it. A [[Vault-Tec employee (TV series)|Vault-Tech employee]] approaches their table and starts to talk to them.

[[File:The Trap Cooper at wrap party.png|thumb|right|250px|Bud and the Hawthornes attend the wrap party]]

That night Cassandra and her husband attend the wrap-up party held at Cooper's house.

===[[The Radio]]===
In a video recording featuring the final moments between Cassandra and her husband. As Lloyd records his self-confessed final words, Cassandra tries to barricade the doorway to protect them from the [[Gulper (TV series)|gulper]] just outside that broke in and devoured them both. The gulper was later found out to have been named [[Peter (TV series)|Peter]] and was Overseer [[Benjamin (TV series)|Benjamin's]] maternal Great Uncle.

==Personality==
On camera, despite claiming she was so nervous, she portrayed herself to be calm and confident, in contrast, to her husband.

==Notable quotes==
* {{Inline quote|That's right. And we'll be living and working right here in Vault 4, leading a community governed by scientists.|Cassandra talking to the TV camera}}

==Appearances==
Cassandra Hawthorne appears only {{in|FOTV}}.
{{FOTV appearances|6=106|7=107}}

==Gallery==
<gallery>
S1E6 Character 20.jpg|Cassandra and Lloyd filming a Vault 4 advertisement
Fallout Season 1 Amazon Vault-Tec.png|Cassandra and Lloyd filming a Vault 4 advertisement with Cooper Howard
</gallery>

{{Navbox characters FOTV}}

[[Category:Fallout TV series human characters]]
[[Category:Vault 4 characters]]
[[ru:ﾐ墟ｰﾑ・・ｰﾐｽﾐｴﾑﾐｰ ﾐ･ﾐｾﾑひｾﾑﾐｽ]]

================ cathy__tv_series__raw.json ================
{{Infobox character
|games       =FOTV
|image       =FoTV Cathy.jpg
|race        =[[Human]]
|gender      =Female
|family      =
|location    =[[Vault 4]]
|affiliation =[[Vault 4]]
|TV actor    =
}}

'''Cathy''' is a character {{In|FOTV}}.

==''Fallout'' TV series==
===[[The Radio]]===
Cathy is a [[Vault 4]] dweller who brings supplies for [[Lucy MacLean|Lucy]] to take with her when she is sentenced to banishment.

==Appearances==
Cathy appears only {{in|FOTV}}.
{{FOTV appearances|7=107}}

==Behind the scenes==
Cathy is portrayed by an uncredited background performer.

{{Navbox characters FOTV}}

[[Category:Fallout TV series human characters]]
[[category:Vault 4 characters]]

================ charles_whiteknife_raw.json ================
{{Infobox character
|games       =FOTV
|image       =FOTV S2E3 Charlie Whiteknife infobox.png
|race        =[[Human]]
|gender      =Male
|nicknames   =Charlie<br />Chuck
|affiliation =[[United States Marine Corps]] (formerly)<br />[[American Veteran Entertainment Alliance]]<br />[[Lee Moldaver|Kate Williams]]
|occupation  =Marine (formerly)<br />Actor (formerly)
|rank        =Corporal
|family      =
|TV actor    =[[Dallas Goldtooth]]
|stunt double=[[Troy Brown]]
}}

{{Quotation|We like to tell stories about what we did out there. Yeah, not all of them, anyways. Some of them we can't tell. But the ones we do tell... we tell 'em to make us feel good about what we did. To give us hope that it was all for the right reasons. But we're just Marines. We don't get the privilege of knowing. We just had to go off of what they told us. They told us that it was all on the line... fate of the whole free world. With the stakes stacked that high... we didn't get much choice, did we? And I guarantee you, the guys on the other side got told the same shit. At the end of the day, we just gotta hope that we bet on the right side. The side that protects the people you love. Because if it did... I guess that's worth doing pretty much anything. Even something bad.|Charlie's speech to the [[American Veteran Entertainment Alliance]]|"[[The Profligate]]"}}

'''Charles "Charlie" Whiteknife''' is a [[Native Americans|Native American]] actor and close friend of [[The Ghoul|Cooper Howard]] in the pre-[[Great War|War]] era.

==Background==
During the [[Sino-American War]], Charlie Whiteknife served in the [[United States Marine Corps|Marine Corps]] alongside [[The Ghoul|Cooper Howard]], eventually attaining the rank of corporal.<ref>[[Robert House]]: ''"Corporal Charlie Whiteknife."''<br />[[The Ghoul|Cooper Howard]]: ''"Yeah. Yeah, Charlie."''<br />Robert House: ''"Rumor has it, he's a bit of a pinko. Is that right?"''<br />({{FOTV|2|3}})</ref><ref>Insignia on Whiteknife's uniform, seen [[:File:Fallout-S2-ghoul-pre-war-2048x1365.jpg|here]].</ref> The two of them served together on the [[Alaska]]n front during the [[Battle of Anchorage]], and in one occasion, Charlie saved Cooper's life during an attack on their squad.<ref>Charles Whiteknife: ''"Now, remember, these are the 45s. They're hard as hell to walk in. And this Power Armor's so goddamned hot from the fires that it's melting the snow beneath my feet. And I'm dragging this guy, you know, just dragging him through the mud and the slush. And I don't know if this poor damn grunt is dead or alive. So, the first chance I get, I take cover, take a knee, open up that visor. And who do I see staring right back at me? It's Cooper Howard. That's right. You know what he said to me? Coop. You remember?"''<br />[[The Ghoul|Cooper Howard]]: ''"Uh, 'How do I look?' "''<br />Charles Whiteknife: ''"That's a lie, ladies and gentlemen. That is a lie. I mean, the movie star Cooper Howard, he probably would have said that. But the man I was looking at... he looked up at me and he said, 'How are the others?' Nearly burnt alive... and he was worried about our squad. Fuckin' Marines, huh?"''<br />({{FOTV|2|3}})</ref> After his discharge, he started a career as a [[Hollywood]] movie actor but found he was often typecast as Native American characters in Westerns, many of which he co-starred in with Cooper.<ref>[[Fallout (TV series)|''Fallout'']] Season 1 Episode 6: "[[The Trap]]," ~20:40</ref>

By 2077, he lived in [[Tarzana]], [[Los Angeles]], where he owned five acres of land.<ref>[[Fallout (TV series)|''Fallout'']] Season 1 Episode 6: "[[The Trap]]," ~21:00</ref> At some point, he became affiliated with [[Lee Moldaver|Kate Williams]] and her anti-capitalist, supposedly [[Communism|communist]] group. When this information got out to the public, Charles was blacklisted as a "Hollywood Red," but he no longer cared.<ref>[[Sebastian Leslie]]: ''"Fucking Hollywood Reds. I'm telling you, radicalism is sweeping through Hollywood like a bad case of the clap. Even got your friend, Charlie Whiteknife."''<br />[[The Ghoul|Cooper Howard]]: ''"Are you kidding me? Charlie?"''<br />Sebastian Leslie: ''"Mm."''<br />Cooper Howard: ''"I served with that guy."''<br />Sebastian Leslie: ''"They have meetings and everything. It's a shit show."''<br />({{FOTV|1|6}})</ref> Through his interactions with Williams, he came to perceive the rise of corporate power and its many influences in society and the government with special attention to the [[Vault-Tec Corporation]]'s joint collaboration with the government to build the [[Vault]]s.

==''Fallout'' TV series==
===Season 1===
====[[The Trap]]====
Charlie is first mentioned during a conversation between Cooper Howard and [[Sebastian Leslie]] at a wrap party at the [[Howard residence]], in which Sebastian mentions Charlie as being a "Hollywood Red." This surprises Cooper, given that they had served together in the Marines.

Later, Charlie and Cooper meet up at a bar, where Cooper (half-jokingly) calls out Charlie for skipping the wrap party to attend one of his "Communist meetings," as Cooper describes it. Cooper expresses disapproval towards Charlie for being a part of something they fought against during the [[Sino-American War]]. Charles rebuts that the cause they fought for was meaningless, though Cooper still believes in it (the American Dream). Jokingly, Charlie says that said dream has him getting "shot in the ass by [Cooper] all day." In response, Cooper points out that Charlie is well off by the standards of the American Dream, but Charlie claims that this is meaningless in the face of Vault-Tec, which he calls the devil.

Defensively, Cooper notes that his [[Barb Howard|wife]] works at Vault-Tec and asks if Charlie is by extension calling Barb the devil. Charlie clarifies that he considers Vault-Tec a problem because of its "fiduciary responsibility:" the [[United States government]] had outsourced its survival to Vault-Tec, a corporation which has a fiduciary responsibility to make money for its investors, by selling Vaults. Cooper sees no problem with this, calling it standard capitalism, but Charles argues that if the peace negotiations to end the Sino-American War continue, then Vault-Tec can't continue selling Vaults. Hence, it is Vault-Tec's fiduciary responsibility to ensure that peace never comes.

Cooper asks how Vault-Tec would accomplish this. Charles doesn't know, but offers an analogy, asking Cooper if he remembers a movie they did with a man named [[Johnny Morton]] and reminisces about his role in the movie as a generic [[Native Americans|Native American]]. Cooper tries to upsell Charlie's performance, saying that Charlie played the character Tallhand Mudlake with "grace and dignity." Charlie continues: Morton's character was a rancher who owned half of [[Missouri]] and had more power than the town sheriff played by Cooper; Cooper understands what he means: that when the rancher has more power than the sheriff, the "whole town burns down." Charlie makes his point: Vault-Tec is effectively the rancher, and the U.S. government is the sheriff, and the United States will suffer unless the people do something about the situation.

Cooper downplays Charlie's words as a conspiracy theory and compares him to cultist. However, Charlie argues that Cooper sounds more like a cultist given how fervently he is defending a system that could, in Charlie's view, destroy the world. Before leaving, Charlie leaves Cooper a card for the [[Hollywood Forever]] group and tells him to attend a meeting just to learn about the company where his wife works, for her sake.

The following day, Charlie meets Cooper at Hollywood Forever, just outside of the meeting place, and thanks Cooper for attending. Though Cooper is still uncertain, Charles confidently claims that he'll stay and says there is someone he should meet. The person in question, [[Lee Moldaver|Kate Williams]], arrives just then to greet Cooper.

====[[The Radio]]====
Charles sits beside Cooper as Miss Williams talks to the [[Hollywood Forever meeting attendee]]s about the falsehoods of the American Dream. Once Miss Williams starts to talk about the soldiers who fought abroad, Cooper loses his cool and abruptly tries to leave, though Charles tries to stop him. Miss Williams stops him instead, leading to a debate between her and Cooper. As it starts to get heated, Charles apologizes, claiming it was a mistake bringing Cooper there, and tries to leave with him, but Miss Williams stops him. She states that she was glad that Charles brought Cooper, as she knows Cooper's wife.

===Season 2===
====[[The Profligate]]====
In the Ghoul's flashbacks, Charlie and Cooper attend an event hosted by the [[American Veteran Entertainment Alliance]] where the former is being honored. During the event preparations, the two privately discuss the mission Cooper was given by Kate Williams about getting close to Robert House; Charlie claims he was not told the method, but they both acknowledge, to Cooper's reluctance, that she most likely expects Cooper to assassinate House. Charlie tries to assure his friend that their time in the military has adjusted them to taking a life, that Robert House is just "one man," but Cooper remains uneasy.

Later on, Charlie takes the podium after being introduced by [[Diane Welch|Representative Diane Welch]] and entertains the audience by recalling a war story where he helped save Cooper's life. He laughs off a joke Cooper makes about it and tells the real story about how his comrade, despite being severely injured, asked after the fates of his fellow soldiers first. He then uses that story to give a speech about doing one's duty for the protection of the ones they love, serving as a subtle message to Cooper directly about fulfilling his role in the plan to take down Robert House. After he finishes his speech, he receives a commemorative lighter as an award from Representative Welch.

As the audience leaves, Charlie exits the stage and sits by Cooper. He gives the lighter to Cooper as a gift, saying that he got the award for saving one man (Cooper), not for having killed three people in order to do so, indicating he should reconsider helping their group with the plan against House if it means protecting his family.

====[[The Demon in the Snow]]====
A flashback to Cooper's military service in Alaska shows that Charlie was deployed with him to a recovery mission on one of the Alaskan islands, outfitted with suits of [[T-45 power armor (TV series)|T-45 power armor]]. However, by the time they reached their objective, a combination of combat damage and malfunctioning hardware resulted in their armor starting to show its flaws, including Charlie's entire left arm locking up and preventing him from using his [[T60 pistol (TV series)|weapon]].

Cooper tried to radio their superiors to abort the mission, but unbeknownst to Charlie, he was denied. Cooper lied and told Charlie they were ordered to retreat, and telling Charlie to leave first. Though doubtful, Charlie obliged but warned Cooper to stay close, joking that he dreaded having to face Barb's wrath. Charlie still went on his own, and so he did not see Cooper subsequently being ambushed by PLA soldiers and saved by the intervention of a [[Deathclaw (TV series)|deathclaw]].

==Personality==
During his service in the Marines with Cooper during the Sino-American War, Charlie looked out for him as both a soldier and a friend; on one mission to an Alaskan island, he joked to Cooper that he had to keep them both safe, or else incur Barb's wrath. After starting his Hollywood career, Charles was elevated to a celebrity lifestyle, garnering enough wealth to buy land for himself, but was gradually worn down by his frequent typecasting in Hollywood productions.

Once he met Kate Williams and bought into her anti-capitalist rhetoric, he no longer cared about how he would be perceived by the public, as his focus instead turned to the increasing influence of corporate interests in government. He saw Vault-Tec's joint work with the government to create the [[Vault]]s as an omen of the end of the world due to the concept of fiduciary responsibility requiring them to oppose any potential peace negotiations that would end the ongoing war, thus ensuring that people would continue investing in the Vaults.

Despite knowing that his friend Cooper would be highly distrustful of the group's reputation as communists, Charlie still believed that he could be swayed to see the danger of Vault-Tec's influence like he had, seeing Williams' plan to take down [[Robert House]] as a necessary evil and trusting that Cooper would also come to share their view.

==Appearances==
Charlie Whiteknife appears only {{in|FOTV}}.
{{FOTV appearances
|6=106
|7=107
|11=203
|12=204
}}

==Gallery==
<gallery widths=200>
FOTV Charles Whiteknife.png|Whiteknife in "[[The Trap]]"
Fallout-S2-ghoul-pre-war-2048x1365.jpg|Whiteknife (left) in a season 2 pre-release image
FOTV S2E3 Charlie Whiteknife closeup.png|Whiteknife in "[[The Profligate]]"
</gallery>

==References==
{{References}}

{{Navbox characters FOTV}}

[[Category:Fallout TV series human characters]]
[[Category:United States Marines]]
[[Category:Pre-War actors]]
[[ru:ﾐｧﾐｰﾑﾐｻﾐｸ ﾐ｣ﾐｰﾐｹﾑひｽﾐｰﾐｹﾑЬ]

================ chase_powell_raw.json ================
{{Infobox character
|games       =FOTV
|image       =FOTV Vault 31 Cryobay.png
|race        =[[Human]]
|gender      =
|family      =
|location    =[[Vault 31]]
|role        =Junior executive
|affiliation =[[Vault 31]]/[[Vault-Tec Corporation]]
|TV actor    =
|dod         =
|dod verified=
}}

'''Chase Powell''' is a pre-War junior executive of the [[Vault-Tec Corporation]] who is currently preserved in [[Vault 31]].

==Background==
Powell was a Vault-Tec junior employee selected to participate in [[Bud Askins]]' executive assistant training program "[[Bud's Buds]]," a plan to create "super managers" who would define the future of humanity after the [[Great War]] wiped out all competitors to Vault-Tec. Powell and the other Buds would be kept in [[Cryonics|cryostasis]] in Vault 31, periodically thawed out, and transferred to [[Vault 32]] or [[Vault 33|33]] to manage the dwellers and participate in controlled breeding (eugenics), all under Askins' supervision.<ref>[[Norm MacLean]]: ''"So what's Vault 32 and 33? Just people to be controlled?"''<br />[[Bud Askins]]: ''"What? No! When you put it like that, it sounds downright morally questionable. They're our breeding pool, the ultimate expression of HR R&D. Genetically selected to breed with my Buds to create a class of super managers. People with positivity, people who make lemonade. People who will inherit the Earth after we've wiped the surface clean."''<br />("[[The Beginning]]")</ref><ref name="highly supervised">[[Norm MacLean]]: ''"Is this where my dad's from?"''<br />[[Bud Askins]]: ''"You'll never find out. Oh. He's gonna find out. These are Bud's Buds. My Buds. America outsourced the survival of this country to the private sector. But it would have been insane to keep a failed nation alive. So, we kept Vault-Tec alive instead. A well-trained staff of highly supervised junior executives from my own assistant training program. Because the future of humanity comes down to one word: Management."''<br />("[[The Beginning]]")</ref> As of [[Timeline (2250-2300)#2296|2296]], more than 219 years after the [[Great War]], they remain dormant in stable condition in [[Vault 31]]'s cryo pods.<ref name="fotv107">[[Fallout (TV series)|''Fallout'']], "[[The Radio]]"</ref>

==Appearances==
Chase Powell appears only {{in|FOTV}}.

==References==
{{References}}

[[Category:Fallout TV series mentioned-only characters]]
[[Category:Fallout TV series human characters]]
[[Category:Vault 31 characters]]
[[Category:Vault-Tec characters]]
